柯克：舰长日志，星历5693.2
KIRK: Captain's log, stardate 5693.2.
企业号正在接近最后报告的位置
The Enterprise is approaching the last reported position
星舰挑战号
of the starship Defiant,
三周前消失得无影无踪
which vanished without trace three weeks ago.
我们处于未经勘测的领域
We are in unsurveyed territory.
舰长，我们所有传感器的读数都非常奇怪
Captain, we are registering very curious readings from all sensors.
- 具体说明  - 我不能
- Specify. - I cannot.
根据我们的仪器，空间本身实际上正在分裂
According to our instruments, space itself is literally breaking up.
没有已知的现象可以解释这些读数
There is no known phenomenon which would account for these readings.
- 是不是传感器故障？  - 不是
- What about sensor failure? - Negative.
- 我已经对所有系统进行了检查  - 斯科提：舰长
- I have run a check on all systems. - SCOTTY: Captain.
- 我们正在失去引擎的动力  - 情况有多糟？
- We're losing power in the engines. - How bad is it?
我们几乎读不到它，但我不喜欢它的样子
We can barely read it, but I don't like the looks of it,
也找不到原因
and I cannot find out the cause.
契科夫：舰长
CHEKOV: Captain.
目测正前方有个物体
Visual detection of an object dead ahead.
- 怎么样，史波克？  - 真有趣
- How about it, Spock? - Fascinating.
- 说说  - 几乎没有传感器接触
- Explain. - There is virtually no sensor contact.
没有质量分析，没有辐射痕迹
No mass analysis, no trace of radiation.
我们看到了它，但我们的传感器表明它不存在
We see it, but our sensors indicate it is not there.
挑战号
The Defiant.
苏鲁先生，只有脉冲引擎
Mr. Sulu, impulse engines only.
- 接近传送范围  - 是，长官
- Close to transporter range. - Aye, aye, sir.
上尉，打开呼叫频率
Lieutenant, open up a hailing frequency.
我一直在尝试与他们取得联系，长官，没有回应
I've been trying to raise them, sir. There is no response.
- 正好在传送范围内，长官  - 好的，保持位置
- Just within transporter range, sir. - Good. Maintain position.
史波克先生，契科夫先生，跟我来
Mr. Spock, Mr. Chekov, come with me.
麦考伊医生，立即到传送室报告
Dr. McCoy, report to the transporter room immediately.
- 斯科提，你来掌舵，斯科提：是，长官
- Scotty, you have the con. SCOTTY: Aye, sir.
- 已锁定到挑战号的舰桥上，长官  - 柯克：传送
- Locked in on the Defiant bridge, sir. - KIRK: Energize.
[哔哔声和嗡嗡声]
[BEEPING AND WHIRRING]
柯克：宇宙，最后的边疆
KIRK: Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
以前在星舰上发生过叛乱吗？
Has there ever been a mutiny on a starship before?
绝对没有此类事件的记录，少尉
Absolutely no record of such an occurrence, ensign.
麦考伊：吉姆
McCOY: Jim.
舰长的脖子断了
The captain's neck is broken.
船还在运作，舰长
The ship is still functioning, captain.
合理假设，叛变者在船上的某个地方
It is logical to assume the mutineers are somewhere aboard.
使用船上的传感器来定位它们
Use the ship's sensors to locate them.
柯克呼叫企业号
Kirk to Enterprise.
斯科提[通过无线电]：我是斯科特
SCOTTY [OVER RADIO]: Scott here.
准备按我的命令传送一支完整的安全小队过来
Prepare to beam over a full security squad on my orders.
- 斯科提：是的，舰长  - 舰长
- SCOTTY: Aye, aye, captain. - Captain,
这艘船上没有生命迹象
there is no sign of life aboard this vessel.
奇怪，史波克先生，很奇怪
Odd, Mr. Spock. Very odd.
史波克，你和我呆在这里
Spock, you stay here with me.
契科夫， 下去检查轮机部和生命支持系统
Chekov, get down to Engineering and life-support systems.
麦考伊医生，检查医务室
Dr. McCoy, check out the Sickbay.
柯克呼叫企业号
Kirk to Enterprise.
取消安全小队并等待进一步的指示
Cancel the security squad and stand by for further instructions.
是，舰长，随时待命
Aye, aye, captain. Standing by.
我无法获得挑战号的精确定位，斯科特先生
I can't get an accurate fix on the Defiant, Mr. Scott,
但是我知道它正在远离我们
but I know it's drifting away from us.
我要修正范围吗，长官？
Shall I correct for range, sir?
是的，我觉得你是对的
Aye. I think you're right.
让我们保持在传送范围内，但不要太近
Keep us within beaming range, but not too close.
- 舰长  - 柯克[通过无线电]：报告，契科夫
- Captain. KIRK [OVER RADIO]: Report, Chekov.
就像我在生命支持中发现的一样
Just like what I found in Life Support.
都死了
All dead.
上来吧
Get back up here.
- 柯克呼叫麦考伊  - 我是麦考伊
- Kirk to McCoy. - McCoy here.
老骨头，你能告诉我他们都是怎么死的吗？
Bones, can you tell me what they all died of?
麦考伊[通过无线电]：我说这些人是互相残杀的
McCOY [OVER RADIO]: I'd say these people killed each other.
他们什么？
They what?
你没听错，吉姆，这些人互相残杀
You heard correctly, Jim. These people killed each other.
精神疾病会感染所有船员吗？
Could mental disease have infected all of the crew?
根据飞船日志
According to the ship's log,
这里的外科医生甚至不知道发生了什么
the medical surgeon down here didn't even know what was going on.
我尽可能收集所有数据
The best I can do is get all the readings I can get
稍后分析它们
and analyze them later.
什么鬼…？
What the devil...?
柯克：老骨头，是什么？
KIRK: Bones, what is it?
老骨头，是什么？
Bones, what is it?
回答我
Answer me.
- 回答我  - 吉姆，这艘船正在解体
- Answer me. - Jim, this ship is dissolving.
我的手刚刚穿过一个人和一张桌子
My hand just passed through a man and a table.
立刻上来
Get back up here on the double.
斯科特先生，挑战号开始消失了
Mr. Scott, the Defiant. It's starting to disappear.
斯科提[通过无线电]：舰桥呼叫传送室
SCOTTY [OVER RADIO]: Bridge to transporter room.
传送室，我是奥尼尔
Transporter room. O'Neil here.
你修好传送装置了吗，先生？
You got that transporter working, mister?
不，长官，还没有
No, sir. Not yet.
苏鲁先生，你接手，我去传送室
Take over, Mr. Sulu. I'll be in the transporter room.
是，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
船长，挑战号的传感器
Captain, the Defiant's sensors correspond with an extremely
与企业号的传感器具有极高的相关性
high degree of correlation to those of the Enterprise.
你是说挑战号上发生的事
You mean what happened to the Defiant
企业号上可能也在发生？
might be happening to the Enterprise?
是的
Affirmative.
- 柯克呼叫企业号，斯科特先生  - 斯科提[通过无线电]：我是斯科特
- Kirk to Enterprise. Mr. Scott. SCOTTY [OVER RADIO]: Scott here.
斯科特先生，准备传送我们回去
Mr. Scott, stand by to beam us back.
- 我不能，长官，不能一次传送所有人  - 为什么不能？发生了什么？
- I can't, sir. At least not all at once. - Why not? What's happen--?
一切，你所在的那艘船正在消失
Everything. That ship you're in is fading out
它正在…它正在撕扯这艘船的内部结构
and it's-- Well, it's ripping the innards out of this one.
它干扰了我们的传送频率
It's jamming our transporter frequencies.
只有其中三个在工作，并且我没有把握
I've only got three of them working, and I'm not sure of those.
你们中的一个人得等等
One of you has got to wait.
契科夫，麦考伊，准备传送
Chekov, McCoy, prepare for transportation.
你也是，史波克
You too, Spock.
请求允许我留下，舰长
Request permission to remain, captain.
- 我可以收集完整数据  - 拒绝请求
- I could be completing the data. - Request denied.
舰长，有风险…
Captain, there is a chance--
我知道有什么风险，史波克先生
I know what the chances are, Mr. Spock.
不要争了，带着资料回去
Don't argue. Get back with the information.
我马上过去
I'll be right there.
- 斯科提，启动传送装置  - 是
- Scotty, energize transporter. - Aye.
史波克：传送
SPOCK: Energize.
它消失了
It's gone.
挑战号就这样消失了
The Defiant just vanished.
有发现吗？
Anything?
史波克：没有
SPOCK: Negative.
就是这样，我已经尽力了
That's it. I've done all I can.
外面没有什么可以抓住并带进来的
There's nothing out there to grab a hold of and bring in.
那艘船走的时候，肯定带走了舰长
When that ship went, it must have taken the captain with it.
女人的声音[在电脑上]：电脑工作中
WOMAN'S VOICE [ON COMPUTER]: Computer working.
计算空间分裂间期的下一个周期
Compute the next period of spatial interphase.
距下一次分裂间期2小时12分钟
Next interphase two hours, 12 minutes.
2小时12分钟？
Two hours and 12 minutes?
能量泄漏对船造成了损坏，她开始漂移了
That power leak has done damage to the ship, and she's starting to drift.
我不能保持她在原地那么久
I can't hold her in place that long.
我们必须试试，斯科特先生，这里的空间结构非常薄弱
We must try, Mr. Scott. The fabric of space is very weak here.
如果我们干扰它，就没有机会救回舰长了
If we disturb it, there will be no chance of retrieving the captain alive.
我不明白这个空间区域有什么特别之处
I don't understand what's so special about this region of space.
可以这样想，契科夫先生
Picture it this way, Mr. Chekov.
我们存在的宇宙与其他众多宇宙共存
We exist in a universe which coexists with a multitude of others
在同一个物理空间中
in the same physical space.
在特定的短暂时间内
At certain brief periods of time,
他们的空间区域与我们的区域重叠
an area of their space overlaps an area of ours.
那就是分裂间期的时间
That is the time of interphase,
在此期间，我们可以和挑战号的宇宙联系
during which we can connect with the Defiant's universe.
史波克先生？
Mr. Spock?
到时候我们就能找回舰长了，不是吗？
We will be able to retrieve the captain at that time, won't we?
是的，然而，每个宇宙的维度结构
Yes. However, the dimensional structure of each universe
完全不一样，任何能量的使用都会干扰它
is totally dissimilar. Any use of power disturbs it.
如果我们不是特别小心
If we are not extremely careful,
我们将失去舰长，而我们自己也会被困住
we shall lose the captain and become trapped ourselves.
- 我明白了  - 像他一样死去？
- I see. - And die like him?
[尖叫和咕噜声]
[SCREAMING AND GRUNTING]
契科夫
Chekov.
- 契科夫！  - 啊！
- Chekov! - Aah!
- 史波克：让警卫到舰桥  - 是，长官
- SPOCK: Security guards to the Bridge. - Aye, sir.
发生什么事了，史波克先生？
What happened, Mr. Spock?
在他攻击时，我正试图向契科夫先生解释
I was attempting to explain to Mr. Chekov
这种情况下我们问题的原理
the nature of our problems in this situation when he attacked.
有没有人注意到在这之前他的行为有什么异常？
Did anyone notice anything peculiar in his behavior before this?
我想他有几次疼痛痉挛
I think he had several spasms of pain.
- 他似乎变得有些疯狂？  - 医生
- Did he seem to be getting hysterical? - Doctor,
他更像是愤怒而不是害怕
he seemed more angry than frightened.
他没有理由愤怒
He had no cause to be angry.
带契科夫先生去医务室，把他束缚起来
Take Mr. Chekov to Sickbay. Put him under restraint.
乌胡拉上尉是对的，契科夫心中充满了杀人的愤怒
Lieutenant Uhura is correct. There was murderous fury in Chekov,
同样的愤怒在挑战号上很明显
the same fury which was evident in the Defiant.
那就是我害怕的
That's what I was afraid of.
无论是什么驱使挑战号的船员互相残杀
Whatever it was that drove the crew of the Defiant to murder each other
可能是有传染性的
could be communicable.
你需要什么东西来找出原因？
Is there anything you need to isolate the cause?
时间
Time.
哦，顺便说一下，史波克先生，我认为这可能是一个明智的预防措施
Oh, and by the way, Mr. Spock, I think it might be a wise precaution
让我们与挑战号拉开一些距离
to put some distance between us and the Defiant.
如果我们要找回舰长，我们不能动
If we are to recover the captain, we must not move.
那需要多久？
How long will that take?
大约两小时后才能进行尝试。
Approximately two hours before the attempt can be made.
史波克，你确定吉姆还活着吗？
Spock, are you sure that Jim is still alive?
舰长在我们的传送光束内
The captain was caught in our transporter beam
当挑战号逐渐消失时
when the Defiant phased out.
他有可能幸免于跃迁的冲击并幸存下来
It is possible he was spared the shock of transition and survived.
但是，如果我们要找回他
However, if we are to recover him,
我们必须在下一次分裂间期的精确时刻抓住他
we must catch him at the precise moment during the next interphase,
否则他会死，而且没有容错的余地
or he will die, and there can be no margin for error.
他的环境装置能提供可呼吸的空气
His environmental unit can provide breathable air
不超过3.62小时
for no more than 3.62 hours.
史波克先生，一艘船只在拦截航线上靠近
Mr. Spock. A vessel approaching on an intercept vector.
- 状态，苏鲁先生  - 距离200,000公里
- Status, Mr. Sulu. - Range 200,000 kilometers.
速度0.510
Velocity 0.510.
- 乌乎拉中尉，发出红色警报  - 是的，长官，红色警报
- Lieutenant Uhura, signal red alert. - Aye, sir. Red alert.
所有甲板进入红色警戒状态
All decks go to red alert.
[警报声]
[ALARM WAILING]
女声[在电脑上]：安全确认
WOMAN'S VOICE [ON COMPUTER]: Security confirmed.
[哔哔声]
[BEEPING]
安全确认，好的
Security confirmed. Will do.
他们完全停下了，长官，距离90,000公里并保持
They've stopped dead, sir. Range 90,000 kilometers and holding.
史波克先生？我正在接收视觉信号
Mr. Spock? I'm receiving a visual signal.
切换到主显示器
Transfer to main viewer.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
洛斯肯[通过显示器]：我是指挥官洛斯肯
LOSKENE [OVER MONITOR]: I am Commander Loskene.
你们正在入侵索利安联合体的附属领土
You are trespassing in a territorial annex of the Tholian Assembly.
你们必须立即离开该区域
You must leave this area immediately.
史波克，指挥联邦星舰企业号
Spock, in command of the Federation starship Enterprise.
指挥官，根据联邦记录，这个区域是自由空间
Commander, according to the Federation, this area is free space.
这是我们的领土，我们准备使用武力
We claim this territory and are prepared to use force,
来保护我们的所有权，如有必要
if necessary, to protect our property.
史波克：我们对你们的武力展示不感兴趣
SPOCK: We are not interested in your display of force.
企业号正在响应我们一艘船的求救信号
The Enterprise is responding to a distress signal from one of our ships
目前正在从事救援行动
and is currently engaged in rescue operations.
- 你想帮助我们吗？  - 我没有发现一艘残破的​​船的证据
- Do you wish to assist us? - I find no evidence of a disabled ship.
我的仪器表明我们是该区域仅有的两艘船
My instruments indicate that ours are the only two vessels in this area.
另一艘船在空间上被困住了
The other ship is interspatially trapped.
它应该会在1小时53分钟后重新出现
It should reappear in one hour and 53 minutes.
- 我们请求您在此之前等待  - 很好，企业号
- We request you stand by until then. - Very well, Enterprise.
为了星际友好
In the interest of interstellar amity,
我们将等1小时53分钟
we will wait precisely one hour and 53 minutes.
但要指出，我们不能容忍欺骗
But be correct. We do not tolerate deceit.
如果我们能找到合适的过滤剂
If we could only find the proper filtering agent,
我们或许可以解决这个问题
we might be able to solve this problem.
不行，第三次失败了
Negative. It's the third failure.
我告诉你，护士，拿这个样本进行分析
I tell you, nurse, take this sample and run an analysis on it.
好的，医生
Yes, doctor.
- 舰桥呼叫传送室  - 这里是传送室
- Bridge to transporter room. - Transporter room here.
史波克[通过无线电]：20秒内进入分裂间期
SPOCK [OVER RADIO]: Ready for interphase in 20 seconds.
麦考伊医生！
Dr. McCoy!
[咕噜声]
[GRUNTING]
谢谢你，护士，呼叫警卫
Thank you, nurse. Call security.
我想对这个人进行一些检查
I wanna have some checks run on this man.
锁定柯克舰长的坐标
Lock onto Captain Kirk's coordinates
准备把他带上船，斯科特先生
and prepare to bring him aboard, Mr. Scott.
[哔哔声]
[BEEPING]
- 带他上船，斯科特先生  - 我正在努力
- Bring him aboard, Mr. Scott. - I'm trying.
柯克舰长不在他指定的坐标上，史波克先生
Captain Kirk is not on his designated coordinates, Mr. Spock.
好吧，继续努力，斯科特先生
Well, keep trying, Mr. Scott.
苏鲁上尉，评估
Lieutenant Sulu, evaluation.
传感器读数
Sensor readings are not corresponding
与我们上次看到挑战号时收到的读数不对应
to those we received the last time we saw the Defiant.
有可能索利安人进入该区域扰乱了空间
It is possible the Tholian entry into the area has disturbed the space.
如果发生了这种情况…
And if that has occurred...
麦考伊[通过无线电]：麦考伊呼叫舰桥
McCOY [OVER RADIO]: McCoy to Bridge.
我是史波克
Spock here.
舰长传送上船了吗？
Has the captain been beamed aboard yet?
没有，医生
Negative, doctor.
那么，分裂间期什么时候会发生？
Well, when is that interphase gonna happen?
理论上，已经发生了，医生
Theoretically, it already has happened, doctor.
然而，船上的传感器并没有像预测的那样做出反应
However, the ship's sensors are not responding as predicted.
- 我认为你让事情超时了  - 是的，医生
- I thought you had the thing timed out. - I did, doctor.
这个空间被索利安人扰乱了
The space was disturbed by the Tholians.
你不知道能不能救回舰长？
You don't know whether you're gonna be able to recover the captain or not?
这次分裂间期不行，我将不得不重新计算
Not at this interphase. I shall have to recalculate
以确定下一次分裂间期何时发生
to determine when the next interphase will occur.
它们不会定期发生
They do not take place at regular intervals.
你等不及下一个了，我们还有一个像契科夫这样的案例
You can't wait for the next one. We've had another case like Chekov.
我不得不将我的勤务兵关在医务室
I've had to confine my orderly to Sickbay.
我有信心你很快就会查明原因，医生
I have confidence that you will soon isolate the cause, doctor,
并防止疾病进一步蔓延
and prevent any further spread of the affliction.
史波克先生，这种疾病不是由人传染的
The disease is not transmitted by the men, Mr. Spock.
原因是我们所处的空间区域
The cause is the area of space we're in.
它正在影响全体船员
It's affecting the whole crew.
中枢神经系统中
The molecular structure of the brain tissues
脑组织的分子结构正在扭曲
in the central nervous system are distorting.
影响了挑战号船员的疯狂
And the madness that affected the Defiant's crew
很快就会发生在企业号身上
will soon happen to the Enterprise.
现在，你必须让这艘船离开这里
Now, you've got to get this ship out of here.
史波克先生，我们被攻击了
Mr. Spock, we're being fired upon.
[爆炸]
[EXPLOSION]
- 著名的索利安式守时  - 史波克先生
- The renowned Tholian punctuality. - Mr. Spock.
损坏控制报告
Damage control report.
A-4和C-13区有轻微结构损坏
Minor structural damage to sections A-4 and C-13.
轮机部，保持动力稳定
Engineering, hold power steady
并切断所有不必要的消耗
and cut off all unnecessary expenditures.
苏鲁先生，除了紧急维护动力外，所有的能量都转移到护盾上
Mr. Sulu, divert all but emergency maintenance power to the shields.
但是先生，这会使我们的相位炮能量降低50%
But sir, that will reduce our phaser power by 50 percent.
史波克先生！
Mr. Spock!
[爆炸]
[EXPLOSION]
斯科特呼叫舰桥
Scott to Bridge.
我是史波克
Spock here.
斯科提[通过无线电]：我知道你不喜欢使用相位炮
SCOTTY [OVER RADIO]: I know you don't like to use the phasers,
但你必须对那里的那艘船做些什么
but you've got to do something about that ship out there.
明白了，乌乎拉上尉，呼叫索利安飞船
Understood. Lieutenant Uhura, open a channel to the Tholian ship.
- 是的，长官  - 苏鲁先生
- Aye, sir. - Mr. Sulu,
- 锁定相位炮跟踪控制  - 相位炮已锁定，长官
- lock in phaser tracking controls. - Phasers locked in, sir.
所有频率都无响应，长官
There's no response on any frequency, sir.
这场战斗有什么用，史波克？你已经失去了吉姆
What's the use of this battle, Spock? You've lost Jim.
- 带船离开这里  - 准备好了吗，苏鲁先生？
- Take the ship out of here. - Ready, Mr. Sulu?
[机器哔哔声]
[MACHINES BEEPING]
准备好了，史波克先生
Ready, Mr. Spock.
发射
Fire.
命中，史波克先生
A hit, Mr. Spock.
轮机部，状态报告
Engineering, status report.
- 斯科特先生？  - 斯科提：史波克
- Mr. Scott? - SCOTTY: Spock,
索利安人刚才的攻击烧毁了了我们的动力供应转换器
that hit we took from the Tholians has fused our power supply converters.
我现在对企业号无能为力，她一定会漂移
I can't do a thing with the Enterprise now. She's bound to drift.
也许就在外面那个门洞里
Maybe right through that doorway out there.
你能估计维修所需的最短时间吗？
Can you estimate minimum time required for repair?
我甚至不知道她是否能修好
I don't even know if she can be repaired.
你满意了吗？
Are you satisfied?
- 史波克，你为什么要这么做？  - 战斗的决定是合乎逻辑的
- Spock, why did you do it? - The decision to fight was logical.
时间不够所以无法采取任何其他行动
Lack of time prevented any other course of action.
索利安船必须被重创
The Tholian ship had to be disabled.
你应该知道会发生什么
You should have known what could have happened
并竭尽全力保护你的船员
and done everything in your power to safeguard your crew.
那是星舰舰长的标准，像吉姆
That is the mark of a starship captain. Like Jim.
医生，我不认为现在是比较的时候
Doctor, I hardly believe this is the time for comparisons.
请马上去你的实验室
Please go at once to your laboratory
并寻找空间影响的解药
and search for an antidote to the effects of this space.
那是你的首要任务，因为我们必须留在这里
That is your primary task, since we must remain here.
史波克先生，有东西刚刚进入了传感器范围
Mr. Spock, something has just entered sensor range.
是另一艘索利安飞船，长官
It's another Tholian, sir.
当洛斯肯试图拦截我们时，他一定联系过他们
Loskene must have contacted them when he tried to intercept us.
真有趣
Fascinating.
先生，我要锁定剩余的相位炮能量吗？
Shall I lock in remaining phaser power, sir?
不要，乌胡拉上尉
Negative. Lieutenant Uhura,
你能呼叫靠近的船只吗？
can you open a channel to the approaching vessel?
他们拒接，长官，我不能…
They're refusing reception, sir. I can't--
距离，苏鲁先生
Distance, Mr. Sulu.
刚刚超出相位炮射程，长官
Just beyond phaser range, sir.
那是什么？
What is that?
苏鲁先生，我将对这些细丝进行分析
Mr. Sulu, I shall run an analysis on those filaments.
将所有传感器连接到船上图书馆的计算机控制台
Tie in all sensors to the ship's library's computer console.
- 切换扫描器  - 是的先生
- Switch scanners. - Yes, sir.
联邦技术中没有与此结构类似的
There is no analogue to this structure in Federation technology.
不管怎样，它是一个能量场
It is, however, an energy field,
如果索利安人成功地完成了这个结构
and if the Tholians are successful in completing this structure
在我们完成维修之前
before we have completed our repairs,
我们再也回不了家了
we shall not see home again.
医生，你上次报告说没有
Doctor, your last report on an antidote
这个空间的影响的解毒剂
on the effects of this space was negative.
史波克先生，现在还是没有
It's still negative, Mr. Spock.
锡拉根似乎是迄今为止测试过的最有希望的物质
Theragen seems to be the most promising substance tested so far.
- 我们正取得进展 - 这有迫切性需要你
- We're progressing. - The urgency requires your attention
把注意力放在实验室
in the laboratory.
我的员工日以继夜地工作
My staff is working around the clock.
我的在场不会影响任何测试的生物化学性质
My being there will not affect the biochemistry of any of the tests.
史波克先生，这项事务需要我的个人的关注
This service requires my personal attention, Mr. Spock.
几个小时前，舰长选择留在挑战号号上
A few hours ago, the captain elected to remain on board the Defiant
所以他的三名船员
so that three members of his crew
最有可能安全返回企业号
would have the best chance of returning safely to the Enterprise.
他关心的不仅仅是他们
His concern was not only for them,
而是这艘飞船的所有船员
but for all the members of the crew of this ship.
你们都知道事件的后果
You all know the sequence of events.
我们被索利安飞船攻击了
We were fired upon by the Tholian ship.
那时，柯克舰长可能还活着
At that time, Captain Kirk may have been alive.
我认为有必要反击
I deemed it necessary to return the Tholian fire
为了企业号的安全
for the safety of the Enterprise.
索利安船已失去战斗力
The Tholian ship has been disabled,
但作为战斗的结果
but as a result of the battle,
我们必须接受柯克舰长已经不在人世的事实
we must accept the fact that Captain Kirk is no longer alive.
[尖叫]
[SCREAMING]
麦考伊：带他去病房，束缚住他
McCOY: Take him to Sickbay. Put him in restraints.
我不会试图表达柯克船长要求的
I shall not attempt to voice the quality of respect and admiration
那种尊重和钦佩的品质
which Captain Kirk commanded.
你们每个人都必须私下想想评估这一损失
Each of you must evaluate the loss in the privacy of your own thoughts.
立正
Attention.
解散
Dismissed.
舰长室里有一项职责
There is a duty to be performed in the captain's quarters
需要我们去完成
which requires our presence.
可以等一下，医生，我的职责要求我立即出现在舰桥上
It can wait, doctor. My duties require my immediate presence on the bridge.
舰长留下了留言带
The captain left a message tape.
他命令由我们两个一起听
It was his order that it be reviewed by both of us
如果他被宣布死亡的话
should he ever be declared dead.
你刚刚宣布吉姆死了
You have just declared Jim dead.
等一个更合适的时刻，医生
It will wait for a more suitable moment, doctor.
为什么？你害怕它会改变你现在的状态吗？
Why? Are you afraid it will change your present status?
船员的身心状况
The mental and physical state of this crew
是你的责任，医生
are your responsibility, doctor.
目前，它们是您的首要任务
At the moment, they are your top priority.
舰长最后的命令是重中之重
The captain's last order is top priority,
在你接手之前，你要遵守这个命令
and you will honor that order before you take over.
麦考伊：从各个方面来说，他都是英雄
McCOY: He was a hero in every sense of the word,
然而他的生命却白白牺牲了
yet his life was sacrificed for nothing.
能让他的死变得有意义的
The one thing that would have given his death meaning
是企业号的安全
is the safety of the Enterprise.
现在你已经让它变得不可能了，史…
Now you've made that impossible, Mr. S--
我们来这里有一个明确的目的，医生
We came here for a specific purpose, doctor.
麦考伊：也许不是同一个
McCOY: Maybe not the same one.
我真的来这里是为了找出你为什么留下来战斗
I really came here to find out why you stayed and fought.
舰长会留下来找回一名船员
The captain would have remained to recover a member of the crew
冒着自己的生命甚至船的危险
at the risk of his own life or even the ship.
是的，他会的，史波克先生，但你没有做那个决定
Yes, he would, Mr. Spock, but you didn't have that decision to make.
与索利安人战斗你有什么收获？
What did you have to gain by fighting the Tholians?
你本可以通过离开该区域来确保自己的舰长地位
You could have assured yourself of a captaincy by leaving the area,
但你选择留下，为什么？
but you chose to stay. Why?
我不需要向你或任何其他船员解释我的理由
I need not explain my rationale to you or to any other member of this crew.
任何实验都有变化的幅度
There is a margin of variation in any experiment.
虽然机会渺茫
While there was a chance,
但我在法律和道德上都有义务确定船长的状态
I was bound legally and morally to ascertain the captain's status.
你的意思是确定他是否死了
You mean to be sure if he was dead.
- 嗯，你确定了这一点  - 够了，医生
- Well, you made certain of that. - That is enough, doctor.
- 我们都有其他事情要做  - 是的，我有事要做
- We both have other things to do. - Yes, I have something to do.
如果船员要活下来，我必须找到这个空间的解药
If this crew is to survive, I have to find an antidote
你让我们困在其中
to this space you've locked us into.
你将返回你的岗位
You'll return to your duty
一旦我们履行了我们在这里的责任
as soon as we've discharged our responsibilities here.
不着急，史波克先生
There's no hurry, Mr. Spock.
你可能不需要解药
The antidote probably doesn't concern you.
瓦肯人可能是免疫的，所以慢慢来
Vulcans are probably immune, so just take your time.
我必须承认我不了解你，史波克
I must admit I don't understand you, Spock,
但我只是不敢相信你会想要吉姆的指挥权
but I just can't believe that you'd want Jim's command.
你得知道如果你让我们脱离困境
You must know that if you get us out of this situation,
他们会授予你勋章
they'll pin a medal on your chest
让你指挥企业号
and give you command of the Enterprise.
医生，我在指挥企业号
Doctor, I am in command of the Enterprise.
我想摆脱这个困境
I would like to remedy that situation.
如果你认为我的行为不正常，那就解除我的职责
If you believe I have acted irregularly, then relieve me of duty.
这是你作为这艘船的医务人员的特权
That is your prerogative as medical officer of this ship.
柯克[录音]：老骨头，史波克
KIRK [ON TAPE]: Bones, Spock,
既然你在播放这盘磁带，我们就假设我已经死了
since you're playing this tape, we will assume that I am dead,
战术形势危急
and the tactical situation is critical,
你们俩都陷入了殊死搏斗
and both of you are locked in mortal combat.
这意味着，斯波克，你控制着这艘船
It means, Spock, that you have control of the ship
并且可能正在做出你职业生涯中最艰难的决定
and are probably making the most difficult decisions of your career.
我只能提供一小点建议，不管它的价值如何
I can offer only one small piece of advice, for whatever it's worth.
使用你的所有知识和逻辑来拯救这艘飞船
Use every scrap of knowledge and logic you have to save the ship,
但是用直觉的洞察力来缓和你的判断
but temper your judgment with intuitive insight.
我相信你有这些品质，但如果你在自己身上找不到
I believe you have those qualities, but if you can't find them in yourself,
去找麦考伊
seek out McCoy.
征求他的意见，如果你觉得它合理，就采纳
Ask his advice, and if you find it sound, take it.
老骨头，你已经听到我刚刚告诉史波克的话了
Bones, you've heard what I've just told Spock.
如果可以，请帮助他
Help him if you can,
但记住他是舰长
but remember he is the captain.
必须毫无疑问地遵循他的决定
His decisions must be followed without question.
你可能会发现他有人类的洞察力也会犯人类错误
You might find that he is capable of human insight and human error.
他们是最难掩饰的
They are most difficult to defend.
但你会发现他值得同样的忠诚和信任
But you will find that he is deserving of the same loyalty and confidence
就像你们给我的一样
each of you have given me.
保重
Take care.
史波克，我，呃...
Spock, I, uh...
抱歉
I'm sorry.
它确实很伤人，不是吗？
It does hurt, doesn't it?
你让我说什么，医生？
What would you have me say, doctor?
[通讯器哔哔声]
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
我是史波克
Spock here.
斯科提[通过无线电]：史波克先生
SCOTTY [OVER RADIO]: Mr. Spock,
我们有一个关于索利安牵引场的读数
we have a readout on the Tholian tractor field.
我想我们可以估算一下其大概完成时间
I think we can estimate its approximate completion time.
我很快就来
I shall be there shortly.
医生，我相信我们每个人都有各自的任务要完成
Doctor, I believe we each have our respective tasks to complete
在索利安人完成他们的任务之前
before the Tholians complete theirs.
[咕噜声]
[GRUNTING]
乌胡拉：舰长！
UHURA: Captain!
柯克舰长，我们以为你--
Captain Kirk, we thought you were--
乌乎拉：史波克！史--
UHURA: Spock! Mr. S--
- 医生，我刚刚看见了舰长--  - 当然，乌乎拉
- Doctor, I have just seen Captain-- - Of course you have, Uhura.
- 我们都很想见他  - 他活着，他还活着，医生
- We would all like to see him. - He's alive. He's alive, doctor.
- 当然  - 相信我，我确实看见了他
- Of course. - Believe me. I did see him.
我看见了，史波克！史波克先生！
I did. Spock! Mr. Spock!
- 我们去医务室  - 医生
- We're going to Sickbay. - Doctor.
医生，我没有疯
Doctor, I'm not going mad.
我确实看到了柯克舰长
I did see Captain Kirk.
我得去找史波克先生
I've got to get to Mr. Spock.
[咕噜声]
[GRUNTING]
斯科特呼叫舰长，斯科特呼叫舰长
Scott to captain. Scott to captain.
我是史波克，请说，斯科特先生
Spock here. Proceed, Mr. Scott.
我们的一名船员刚刚发疯了，但我们已经控制住了他
One of our crewmen just went berserk, but we have him under control.
向麦考伊医生报告发作前注意到的所有症状，通话完毕
Report to Dr. McCoy all symptoms noted prior to the attack. Spock out.
[咕噜声]
[GRUNTING]
- 麦考伊医生  - 是的，护士
- Dr. McCoy. - Yes, nurse.
我对袭击斯科特轮机长的船员进行了诊断
I have a diagnosis of the crewman who attacked Engineer Scott.
这绝对是由于间隙的恶化影响
It was definitely due to the deteriorative effects of interspace.
是的，它开始在整艘船上普遍传播
Yes, it's beginning to spread generally throughout the ship.
医生，我们有进展吗？
Are we any closer, doctor?
不，除了我肯定它是一种锡拉根衍生物，这就是答案
No, except I'm positive that it's a theragen derivative that's the answer.
最好是下一个
It better be the next one.
[契科夫发出咕噜声然后尖叫]
[CHEKOV GRUNTING THEN SCREAMING]
史波克先生也不相信我，是吗，医生？
Mr. Spock didn't believe me either, did he, doctor?
好吧，除了你，没有人看到它，乌乎拉
Well, nobody saw it but you, Uhura.
那么我没有真的看到他，是吗？
Then I didn't really see him, did I?
我认为是的
I don't think so.
[契科夫继续尖叫]
[CHEKOV CONTINUES SCREAMING]
- 我会变得像契科夫一样吗，医生？  - 不
- Will I become like Chekov, doctor? - No.
我们正在努力工作，我们会找到解药的
We're working hard. We'll find an antidote.
- 我们开始进入分裂间期  - 我很好
- We're beginning to interphase. - I'm all right.
斯科特呼叫舰桥
Scott to Bridge.
史波克[通过无线电]：这里是舰桥，我是史波克
SPOCK [OVER RADIO]: Bridge. Spock here.
- 我们是否正在进入间隙？  - 不是
- Are we slipping into interspace? - Negative.
我们目前相对稳定，你为什么要问？
We are relatively stable at the moment. Why do you ask?
我不相信
I don't believe it.
史波克：怎么了，斯科特先生？
SPOCK: What is it, Mr. Scott?
斯科特先生？
Mr. Scott?
史波克先生，我刚刚看到了柯克舰长
Mr. Spock, I've just seen Captain Kirk.
他和我们一样站在那里，然后他就消失了
He was standing there just as plain as we are. And then he disappeared.
立即向舰桥报告
Report to the bridge immediately.
这听起来像乌乎拉的故事，你认为这里面有什么真相吗？
That sounds like Uhura's story. You suppose there's any truth in it?
在关键时刻，人有时会看到他们想看到的东西
In critical moments, men sometimes see exactly what they wish to see.
你认为他们看到吉姆
Do you suppose they're seeing Jim
是因为他们对你失去了信心吗？
because they've lost confidence in you?
- 我只是在陈述一个事实，医生  - 麦考伊：它变得越来越危险
- I was merely stating a fact, doctor. - McCOY: It's getting critical.
在下层甲板上发生了一些袭击事件
There have been a number of assaults down on the lower decks.
甚至斯科提也受到了影响
Even Scotty's being affected.
如果斯科提倒下，那是我们就没有任何机会
If Scotty goes under, that's the finish of whatever chance we have
让企业号离开这里了
of getting the Enterprise out of here.
麦考伊医生，请交给我
Please leave that to me, Dr. McCoy.
我意识到船员是你最关心的问题
I realize that the crew are your prime concern.
你在实验室对他们最好
You can best serve them in your laboratory.
我要求你在找到补救措施前不要出来
I urge you to confine yourself to it until a remedy has been found.
史波克！
Spock!
呵呵
Heh.
一定是这个空间，它也影响到我了，我…
Must be this space. It's getting to me too. I...
我知道你什么都没做，史波克，我--对不起
I know it's nothing you've done, Spock. I-- I'm sorry.
我明白，医生
I understand, doctor.
我敢肯定，舰长会简单地说：“算了，老骨头，”
I'm sure the captain would simply have said, "Forget it, Bones."
史波克先生，看
Mr. Spock, look.
舰长
Captain.
舰长？
Captain?
舰长
Captain.
- 我没事吧，医生？  - 是的，乌乎拉，你很好
- Am I all right, doctor? - Yes, Uhura, you're fine.
- 那我看到的…  - 是真的
- Then what I saw... - It was real.
柯克舰长还活着？
Captain Kirk's alive?
我们都看到了他，舰长还活着
We all saw him. The captain's still alive.
哦
Oh.
[通讯器哔哔声]
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
查佩尔[通过无线电]：查佩尔护士呼叫麦考伊医生
CHAPEL [OVER RADIO]: Nurse Chapel to Dr. McCoy.
我是麦考伊
McCoy here.
最后一次锡拉根测试的结果为你准备好了，医生
Results of the last theragen test ready for you, doctor.
我马上到
I'll be right there.
你对那个相位炮的担忧是正确的
Then your fears about that phaser were correct.
它在那疯狂的空间结构中炸出了一个洞
It blasted a hole right through that crazy space fabric,
只有天知道它把挑战号送到了哪里
and only heaven knows where it sent the Defiant.
确实，但舰长留了下来，只有重叠时间发生了变化
Exactly. But the captain remained. Only the overlap time changed.
下一次分裂间期将发生在这里，你能做好准备吗？
The next interphase will occur here. Can you be ready?
那大约20分钟，是的，她会再回来的
That will be about 20 minutes. Aye, she'll be back together.
但我们只能积累大约80%的动力
But we'll only have about 80 percent power built up.
必须这样做，斯科特先生
It will have to do, Mr. Scott.
[哔哔声]
[BEEPING]
来
Come.
- 你那里有什么？  - 我请客
- What have you got there? - Compliments of the house.
为了你和船员的健康
To your good health and the health of the crew.
你找到解药了，医生
You've found the antidote, doctor.
是的，我已经让船上的每个人
Yes, and I've ordered it orally or intravenously
口服或静脉注射了
for everyone aboard the ship.
我想请先生们喝下它
I would like for you gentlemen to drink it down.
契科夫少尉很早就受到了影响，这对他有作用吗？
Ensign Chekov was affected so early. Has he responded to it?
他又是笑呵呵的样子了，我已经让他离开了病房
He is his smiling self again, and I've discharged him from Sickbay.
- 斯科提：这是什么？  - 它是一种稀释的锡拉根衍生物
- SCOTTY: What is it? - It's a diluted theragen derivative.
锡拉根？克林贡人使用的一种神经毒气
Theragen? A nerve gas used by the Klingons.
是的，也是致命的
Aye, and deadly too.
你在想什么？你想杀了我们所有人
What are you thinking of? You're trying to kill us all.
如果我没记错的话，它会造成死亡
If I remember correctly, it caused fatality
只有在以纯净方式使用时
only when used in pure form.
没错，在这个衍生物中，混合了酒精
That's right, and in this derivative, mixed with alcohol,
它只是抑制大脑的某些神经输入
it merely deadens certain nerve inputs to the brain.
哦，好吧，任何像样的苏格兰威士忌都能做到
Oh, well, any decent brand of Scotch will do that.
唔，一大口这个，你可以用相位枪击晕一个人
Mm. One good slug of this and you could hit a man with phaser stun
而他永远不会感觉到，甚至不知道
and he'd never feel it or even know it.
它与苏格兰威士忌搭配得很好吗？
Does it make a good mix with Scotch?
是的
It should.
我会告诉你的
I'll let you know.
喝下去，史波克，这是人类该做的事
Drink it down, Spock. It's the human thing to do.
这是医嘱，舰长
That's a medical order, captain.
[警报声]
[ALARMS BEEPING]
- 欢迎回来，上尉  - 谢谢，长官
- Welcome back, lieutenant. - Thank you, sir.
契科夫先生，我深切地感受到了您的缺席
Your absence was keenly felt, Mr. Chekov.
谢谢，史波克先生
Thank you, Mr. Spock.
索利安网的估计完成时间
Estimated time for completion of the Tholian web.
两分钟，长官
Two minutes, sir.
船上的计算机是否经过编程以进入间隙？
Are the ship's computers programmed for entry into interspace?
是的，长官，飞船可以随时驶入间隙
Yes, sir. The ship can drive into interspace at any time.
- 史波克呼叫轮机部  - 我是斯科特
- Spock to Engineering. - Scott here.
准备15秒内进入分裂间期
Prepare for interphase in 15 seconds.
斯科提[通过无线电]：是的，长官，待命中
SCOTTY [OVER RADIO]: Aye, sir. Standing by.
史波克先生，他们正准备封上网格
Mr. Spock, they're getting ready to close the web.
十秒内进入分裂间期，九，八
Interphase in ten seconds. Nine, eight,
七、六、五…
seven, six, five...
- 满功率待命  - 她最多只有76%
- Stand by with full power. - She's only up to 76 percent.
- 它必须这样做  - 一
- It will have to do. - One.
准备按我的命令传送
Ready to transport on my order.
- 我看见他了  - 他在那
- I see him. - There he is.
是舰长
It's the captain.
- 先生，牵引场已启动  - 我们正在被拉出这里
- Sir, the tractor field is activated. - We're being pulled out of here.
尽量保持位置，苏鲁先生
Try to maintain position, Mr. Sulu.
我不能，长官
I can't, sir.
轮机部，把飞船动力拉满
Engineering, bring ship's power up to full capability.
[爆炸]
[EXPLOSION]
我们现在在哪里，史波克先生？
Where are we now, Mr. Spock?
舰长，我们已经摧毁了索利安人的网
Captain, we have destroyed the Tholians' web.
没有，少尉，我们利用飞船的动力摆脱了它
Negative, ensign. Utilizing ship's power has thrown us clear of it.
计算与原始位置的距离
Compute the distance from the original location.
- 马上，长官  - 我们失去了舰长吗？
- At once, sir. - Have we lost the captain?
我们很快就会看到，上尉
We shall soon see, lieutenant.
这艘船被精确地拉出了2.72秒差距
The ship has been drawn exactly 2.72 parsecs
远离我们之前的位置
distant from our previous position.
好的，因为舰长被锁在我们的传送光束里
Good. Since the captain was locked into our transporter beam
当我们被甩出分裂间期区域时
when we were thrown clear of the interphase area,
他应该和我们一起被拉到这里来了
he should have been drawn here with us.
- 史波克呼叫传送室  - 我是麦考伊
- Spock to transporter room. - McCoy here.
史波克：舰长的氧气供应快用完了
SPOCK: The captain's oxygen supply is running out now.
你准备好给他注射三氧化合物了吗？
Are you standing by with a hypo of triox compound for him?
准备好了，史波克先生
Ready, Mr. Spock.
准备按照我的命令在舰长的坐标上进行传送
Prepare to transport on the captain's coordinates on my order.
奥尼尔：准备好了，史波克先生
O'NEIL: Ready, Mr. Spock.
史波克先生，是他，是舰长！
Mr. Spock, it's him. It's the captain!
我看到他了，少尉
I see him, ensign.
我看见他了
I see him.
现在，医生
Now, doctor.
[哔哔声和嗡嗡声]
[BEEPING AND WHIRRING]
- 老骨头  - 欢迎回家，吉姆
- Bones. - Welcome home, Jim.
在挑战号被扔出后，我拥有了一个属于自己的整个宇宙
I had a whole universe to myself after the Defiant was thrown out.
里面绝对没有其他人
There was absolutely no one else in it.
我必须说，我更喜欢拥挤的宇宙
I must say, I prefer a crowded universe much better.
没有我你们两个怎么和谐相处的？
How did you two get along without me?
哦，我们将就了一下，呃...
Oh, we managed. Uh...
史波克先生下达了命令，我找到了答案
Mr. Spock gave the orders, and I found the answers.
- 好的，你们之间没有问题吗？  - 没有值得报告的，舰长
- Good. No problems between you? - None worth reporting, captain.
- 说来听听  - 史波克：唔
- Try me. - SPOCK: Hmm.
当人类参与时，这种轻微的干扰是不可避免的
Only such minor disturbances as are inevitable when humans are involved.
哪些人类，史波克先生？
Which humans, Mr. Spock?
他的意思是，当人类和瓦肯人走得很近时，吉姆
He means that when humans become involved with Vulcans, Jim.
没错，我明白
Ah, yes. I understand.
我希望我最后的命令有助于解决
I hope my last orders were helpful in solving any problems
你认为不值得报告的任何问题
that you don't feel worth reporting.
命令，舰长？
Orders, captain?
你指的是什么命令，吉姆？
What orders are you referring to, Jim?
我最后的命令
My last orders.
我留给老-- 给你们俩的最后的命令
The last orders that I left for b-- For both of you.
- 最后录制的命令  - 哦，那些命令
- The last taped orders. - Oh, those orders.
嗯，时间不够
Well, there wasn't time.
我们没能有机会听
We never had a chance to listen to them.
史波克：没听，你看，危机降临到我们身上
SPOCK: No, you see, the crisis was upon us
然后很快就过去了，舰长，我们，呃…
and then passed so quickly, captain, that we, eh...
好的，好的
Good. Good.
好吧，我希望我们不会有类似的机会
Well, I hope we won't have similar opportunities
测试那些你们从来没听过的命令
to test those orders, which you never heard.
- 前进，曲速2，苏鲁先生  - 曲速2，长官
- Ahead warp factor 2, Mr. Sulu. - Warp factor 2, sir.